[{"question":"1.The method used to collect information to use through all phases of the project life cycle is called\nA.Responsibility matrix\nB.Organization breakdown structure\nC.Work breakdown structure\nD.Priority matrix\nE.Work package","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"The method suggested is a selective outline of the project called the work breakdown structure.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"2.Jose is looking at a document that outlines the specific tasks and subtasks required to complete the writingof a technical support manual. The method that was probably used to develop the document is most likely\nA.Responsibility matrix\nB.Organization breakdown structure\nC.Work breakdown structure\nD.Priority matrix\nE.Work package","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"The method suggested is a selective outline of the project called the work breakdown structure. The early stagesof developing the outline serve to ensure that all tasks are identified and that participants of the projecthave an understanding of what is to be done.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"3.The first step in creating the necessary information to manage a project is to\nA.Establish project priorities\nB.Define the project scope\nC.Verify the budget available\nD.Assign team members to work on the project\nE.Determine the required completion date","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"B.","help":"Defining the project scope sets the stage for developing a project plan. Project scope is a definition of theend result or mission of your project—a product or service for your client/customer.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"4.Linda has just been assigned a project to develop a new advertising campaign for an established product. Herfirst step should be to\nA.Establish project priorities\nB.Define the project scope\nC.Verify the budget available\nD.Assign team members to work on the project\nE.Determine the required completion date","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"B.","help":"Defining the project scope sets the stage for developing a project plan. Project scope is a definition of theend result or mission of your project—a product or service for your client/customer.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"5.Research shows the most frequently mentioned barrier to project success is\nA.Not enough budget resources\nB.Poor performance by team members\nC.Weak project leadership\nD.Poorly defined scope or mission\nE.Political in-fighting","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"Research clearly shows that a poorly defined scope or mission is the most frequently mentioned barrier to projectsuccess.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"6.An expected output over the life of a project would be classified as\nA.A deliverable\nB.A product\nC.An end object\nD.An objective\nE.A target","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"Major deliverables—the expected outputs over the life of the project.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"7.The first step of project scope definition is to\nA.Analyze the strategic plan\nB.Analyze the current budget plan\nC.Meet with team members\nD.Select team members\nE.Define the overall objective to meet the customer's needs","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"E.","help":"The first step of project scope definition is to define the overall objective to meet your customer's need(s).","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"8.In reviewing the project plan, Susan sees that the first prototype is due by October 12. This would be best classifiedas a\nA.Project target\nB.Limit item\nC.Milestone\nD.Project objective\nE.Critical goal","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"A milestone is a significant event in a project that occurs at a point in time. The milestone schedule showsonly major segments of work; it represents first, rough-cut estimates of time, cost, and resources for theproject.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"9.The ability of 911 emergency systems to identify the caller's phone number and location are considered to bea\nA.Technical requirement\nB.Milestone\nC.Project limit\nD.Project exclusion\nE.Project deliverable","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"More frequently than not, a product or service will have technical requirements to ensure proper performance.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"10.Which of the following is not one of the items that would appear on a project scope checklist?\nA.Deliverables\nB.Technical requirements\nC.Objectives\nD.Work breakdown structure\nE.Reviews with customer","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"See Project Scope Checklist on Page 102.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"11.\"To construct a high-quality, custom home within five months at costs not to exceed $150,000\" is best classifiedas\nA.A deliverable\nB.A milestone\nC.An objective\nD.A limit\nE.An exclusion","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"The first step of project scope definition is to define the overall objective to meet your customer's need(s).For example, as a result of extensive market research a computer software company decides to develop a programthat automatically translates verbal sentences in English to Russian. The project should be completed withinthree years at a cost not to exceed $1.5 million.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"12.The second step in the defining of a project would be to\nA.Analyze the strategic plan\nB.Analyze the current budget plan\nC.Establish project priorities\nD.Select team members\nE.Define the major objectives to meet the customer's needs","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"Quality and the ultimate success of a project are traditionally defined as meeting and/or exceeding the expectationsof the customer and/or upper management in terms of cost (budget), time (schedule), and performance (scope)of the project (see Figure 4.1).","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"13.Which of the following is not one of the basic classifications of project priorities?\nA.Profit\nB.Cost\nC.Time\nD.Performance\nE.All of these are basic classifications","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"One of the primary jobs of a project manager is to manage the trade-offs among time, cost, and performance. Todo so, project managers must define and understand the nature of the priorities of the project.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"14.If a project criterion indicates that the project must meet a specific date, that criterion is classified as\nA.Constrained\nB.Enhanced\nC.Accepted\nD.Limited\nE.Fixed","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"The original parameter is fixed. The project must meet the completion date, specifications and scope of the project,or budget.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"15.Scott has just been given a project that has a specific target date. After discussion with top management hefinds that while the date is important the cost is more important and a slip in delivery would be acceptableif required to meet the cost targets. The target date is best classified as\nA.Constrain\nB.Enhance\nC.Accept\nD.Limit\nE.Optional","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"For which criterion is it tolerable not to meet the original parameters? When trade-offs have to be made, isit permissible for the schedule to slip, to reduce the scope and performance of the project, or to go overbudget?","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"16.The tool used to assist in making project trade-offs between schedule, budget, and performance objectives iscalled a\nA.Responsibility matrix\nB.Work breakdown structure\nC.Project priority matrix\nD.Work package\nE.Criterion matrix","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"One technique found in practice that is useful for this purpose is completing a priority matrix for the projectto identify which criterion is constrained, which should be enhanced, and which can be accepted.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"17.The lowest element in the hierarchical breakdown of the WBS is\nA.A deliverable\nB.A work package\nC.A cost account\nD.A lowest sub deliverable\nE.An object","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"B.","help":"See Figure 4.3 on page 108.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"18.The highest element in the hierarchical breakdown of the WBS is\nA.A work package\nB.Sub deliverables\nC.A cost account\nD.Major deliverables\nE.The project","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"E.","help":"See Figure 4.3 on page 108.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"19.All of the following are true about work packages except\nA.Consume resources\nB.Assigned to only one manager\nC.Have medium to long duration\nD.Definitive starts and stops dates\nE.All of these are true","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"Work packages are short duration tasks that have a definite start and stop point, consume resources, and representcost. Each work package is a control point. A work package manager is responsible for seeing that the packageis completed on time, within budget, and according to technical specifications.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"20.All of the following are usually included in a work package except\nA.What will be done?\nB.The time needed to complete the work.\nC.A single person who is responsible for its completion.\nD.All the costs for the work package.\nE.All of these are included in a work package.","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"E.","help":"Work packages are short duration tasks that have a definite start and stop point, consume resources, and representcost. Each work package is a control point. A work package manager is responsible for seeing that the packageis completed on time, within budget, and according to technical specifications.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"21.The integration of project work packages within the organization's management structure is known as\nA.Responsibility matrix\nB.Organization breakdown structure\nC.Work breakdown structure\nD.Priority matrix\nE.Process breakdown structure","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"B.","help":"In practice, the outcome of this process is the organization breakdown structure (OBS). The OBS depicts how thefirm has organized to discharge work responsibility.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"22.The final step in the creation of a Work Breakdown Structure is to\nA.Code the WBS for tracking\nB.Assign the cost account to a manager\nC.Assign the work package to a manager\nD.Develop the responsibility matrix\nE.All of these are included in the final step","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"The codes are used to define levels and elements in the WBS, organization elements, work packages, and budgetand cost information.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"23.The intersection of the WBS and the OBS is called the\nA.Responsibility matrix\nB.Priority matrix\nC.Work package\nD.Cost account\nE.Project overlap","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"The \"cost account\" is the focal point because all budgets, work assignments, time, cost, and technical performancecome together at this point.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"24.Creating an extranet website or an internal software database system would be most closely associated with the\nA.Responsibility matrix\nB.Organization breakdown structure\nC.Work breakdown structure\nD.Priority matrix\nE.Process breakdown structure","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"The classic WBS is when the project is broken down to the lowest manageable deliverable and subsequent work packages.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"25.If a project is small or of narrow scope and does not require an elaborate system, which of the following isa good choice?\nA.Responsibility matrix\nB.Organization breakdown structure\nC.Work breakdown structure\nD.Priority matrix\nE.Process breakdown structure","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"The RM (sometimes called a linear responsibility chart) summarizes the tasks to be accomplished and who is responsiblefor what on a project.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"26.The project scope statement indicates that the client is responsible for training the people who will be usingthe equipment and that the project team will train the client's trainers. This is an example of:\nA.Project objectives\nB.Deliverables\nC.Limits and exclusions\nD.Technical requirements\nE.Milestones","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"The limits of scope should be defined. Failure to do so can lead to false expectations and to expending resourcesand time on the wrong problem.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"27.The tendency for the project deliverables to expand over time—usually by changing requirements, specifications,and priorities—is called:\nA.Scope erosion\nB.Scope creep\nC.Project bloat\nD.Scope enhancement\nE.Project add-ons","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"B.","help":"The tendency for the project scope to expand over time—usually by changing requirements, specifications, andpriorities. Scope creep can be reduced by carefully writing your scope statement.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"28.Which of the following is a good example of a Process Breakdown Structure?\nA.New car prototype\nB.New software program\nC.New computer hardware\nD.New sports stadium\nE.New project management book","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"B.","help":"See Figure 4.4 on Page 112.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"29.Which of the follow is least likely to be included in a Work Package?\nA.Materials\nB.Labor\nC.Overhead\nD.Duration\nE.Responsibilities","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"Work packages are short duration tasks that have a definite start and stop point, consume resources, and representcost.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"30.The Snapshot from Practice dealing with Big Bertha II illustrated how important a project's __________ is tothe successful completion of a project.\nA.Objective\nB.Deliverables\nC.Technical requirements\nD.Milestones\nE.Limits and exclusions","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"See Snapshot from Practice on Page 104.Fill in the Blank Questions","difficulty":"Fill in the Blank Questions"},{"question":"31.A selective outline of the project that ensures the identification of all tasks and an understanding of whatis to be done is called a _______________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"work breakdown structure","help":"Once the scope and deliverables have been identified, the work of the project can be successively subdividedinto smaller and smaller work elements. The outcome of this hierarchical process is called the work breakdownstructure (WBS).","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"32.The first step in planning any project is to ________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"define the project scope","help":"Defining the project scope sets the stage for developing a project plan. Project scope is a definition of theend result or mission of your project—a product or service for your client/customer.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"33.The primary purpose of the first step of defining a project is to identify the ________ for the end user andto focus project plans.","type":"fill-in","answer":"objective","help":"The first step of project scope definition is to define the overall objective to meet your customer's need(s).","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"34.Significant events in a project that occur at a specific point in time, are natural control points, and are easilyrecognized by project participants are known as ___________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"Milestones","help":"A milestone is a significant event in a project that occurs at a point in time. The milestone schedule showsonly major segments of work; it represents first, rough-cut estimates of time, cost, and resources for theproject.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"35.The need for a computer to function in countries having different electrical systems is an example of a ________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"technical requirement","help":"More frequently than not, a product or service will have technical requirements to ensure proper performance.For example, a technical requirement for a personal computer might be the ability to accept 120-volt alternatingcurrent or 240-volt direct current without any adapters or user switches.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"36.The agreement that training will be the responsibility of the customer is an example of a project ________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"limit and exclusion","help":"The limits of scope should be defined. Failure to do so can lead to false expectations and to expending resourcesand time on the wrong problem.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"37.A project parameter such as completion date or cost is ________ if it is fixed and must be met.","type":"fill-in","answer":"constrained","help":"The original parameter is fixed. The project must meet the completion date, specifications and scope of the project,or budget.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"38.Taking advantage of opportunities to reduce costs or accelerate the schedule are examples of project criteriabeing classified as ________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"enhance","help":"In the case of time and cost, this usually means taking advantage of opportunities to either reduce costs orshorten the schedule. Conversely, with regard to performance, enhancing means adding value to the project.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"39.In making project trade-offs, a criteria that is allowed to not meet the original target is classified as ________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"accept","help":"Questions to ask in regards to accept. For which criterion is it tolerable not to meet the original parameters?When trade-offs have to be made, is it permissible for the schedule to slip, to reduce the scope and performanceof the project, or to go over budget?","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"40.Developing a ________ provides a forum for clearly establishing priorities with customers and top managementso as to create shared expectations and avoid misunderstandings.","type":"fill-in","answer":"priority matrix","help":"One technique found in practice that is useful for this purpose is completing a priority matrix for the projectto identify which criterion is constrained, which should be enhanced, and which can be accepted.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"41.The result of subdividing the work of a project into smaller and smaller work elements is called ________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"work breakdown structure","help":"Once the scope and deliverables have been identified, the work of the project can be successively subdividedinto smaller and smaller work elements. The outcome of this hierarchical process is called the work breakdownstructure (WBS).","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"42.The most detailed element in the hierarchical breakdown of the project work to be accomplished is known as the________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"work package","help":"The lowest level of the WBS is called a work package. Work packages are short duration tasks that have a definitestart and stop point, consume resources, and represent cost.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"43.A(n) ________ is a grouping of work packages for monitoring progress and responsibility.","type":"fill-in","answer":"cost account","help":"See Figure 4.3 on Page 108.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"44.Practice suggests that a work package should not exceed ________ workdays or one reporting period.","type":"fill-in","answer":"ten","help":"Practice suggests a work package should not exceed 10 workdays or one reporting period. If a work package hasa duration exceeding 10 days, check or monitoring points should be established within the duration, say,every three to five days, so progress and problems can be identified before too much time has passed.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"45.The process of assigning specific work packages to a particular group or person within the organization is called________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"organization breakdown structure","help":"The WBS is used to link the organizational units responsible for performing the work. In practice, the outcomeof this process is the organization breakdown structure (OBS).","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"46.The final step in the defining of a project is focused on assigning ________ to each of the work packages.","type":"fill-in","answer":"codes","help":"Gaining the maximum usefulness of a breakdown structure depends on a coding system. The codes are used to definelevels and elements in the WBS, organization elements, work packages, and budget and cost information.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"47.In a work breakdown structure the ________ is the focal point because all budgets, work assignments, time, cost,and technical performance come together at that point.","type":"fill-in","answer":"cost account","help":"The \"cost account\" is the focal point because all budgets, work assignments time, cost, and technical performancecome together at this point.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"48.Once the __________ has been established, it is the basis for making trade-off decisions later in the project.","type":"fill-in","answer":"Priority Matrix","help":"If midway through the project, a trade-off must be made between cost and expediting, which criterion has priority?One technique found in practice that is useful for this purpose is completing a priority matrix for the projectto identify which criterion is constrained, which should be enhanced, and which can be accepted.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"49.In a ________ the project is organized around phases or groups of activities rather than the more conventionaldeliverables.","type":"fill-in","answer":"work breakdown structure","help":"Once the scope and deliverables have been identified, the work of the project can be successively subdividedinto smaller and smaller work elements. The outcome of this hierarchical process is called the work breakdownstructure (WBS).","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"50.The ________ summarizes, in graphic format, the tasks to be accomplished and who is responsible for what on agiven project.","type":"fill-in","answer":"responsibility matrix","help":"The RM (sometimes called a linear responsibility chart) summarizes the tasks to be accomplished and who is responsiblefor what on a project.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"51.The Work Breakdown Structure is an outline of the project with different levels of __________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"detail","help":"The WBS is an outline of the project with different levels of detail.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"52.The purposes of the ____________ are to provide a framework to summarize organization unit work performance,identify organization units responsible for work packages, and tie the organizational unit to cost controlaccounts.","type":"fill-in","answer":"OBS (Organization Breakdown Structure)","help":"The purposes of the OBS are to provide a framework to summarize organization unit work performance, identifyorganization units responsible for work packages, and tie the organizational unit to cost control accounts.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"53.The most commonly used method for coding the WBS is __________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"numeric indention","help":"The most commonly used scheme in practice is numeric indention.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"54.The gradual expansion of project requirements during the execution of project is known as __________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"scope creep","help":"Scope describes what you expect to deliver to your customer when the project is complete. Your project scopeshould define the results to be achieved in specific, tangible, and measurable terms.True / False Questions","difficulty":"True / False Questions"},{"question":"55.The development of a work breakdown structure with appropriate dates and budget is usually accomplished in asingle iteration.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"The WBS is an outline of the project with different levels of detail.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"56.Studies suggest that there is a strong correlation between project success and clear project scope definition.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Research clearly shows that a poorly defined scope or mission is the most frequently mentioned barrier to projectsuccess.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"57.Project scope describes what you expect to deliver to your customers when the project is complete.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Project scope is a definition of the end result or mission of your project—a product or service for your client/customer.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"58.One of the items included on a project scope checklist is the reviews with the customer.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"See Project Scope Checklist on Page 102.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"59.Quality and the ultimate success of a project are traditionally defined as meeting or exceeding the expectationsof the customer or management.Refer to Figure 4.1","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Quality and the ultimate success of a project are traditionally defined as meeting and/or exceeding the expectationsof the customer and/or upper management in terms of cost (budget), time (schedule), and performance (scope)of the project (see Figure 4.1).","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"60.The criteria for project success include attaining objectives relating to cost, schedule, and revenue.Refer to Figure 4.1","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"Quality and the ultimate success of a project are traditionally defined as meeting and/or exceeding the expectationsof the customer and/or upper management in terms of cost (budget), time (schedule), and performance (scope)of the project (see Figure 4.1).","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"61.Statements of project scope are sometimes referred to as Statements of Work or Project Charters.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Many companies engaged in contracted work refer to scope statements as statements of work (SOW). Other organizationsuse the term project charter. However, the term project charter has emerged to have a special meaning inthe world of project management. A project charter refers to a document that authorizes the project managerto initiate and lead the project.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"62.If a project criterion should be optimized if at all possible, it is classified as being constrained.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"The original parameter is fixed. The project must meet the completion date, specifications and scope of the project,or budget.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"63.Basically, the WBS is an outline of the project with different levels of detail.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"The WBS is an outline of the project with different levels of detail.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"64.In general, work packages should not exceed 10 work days.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Practice suggests a work package should not exceed 10 workdays or one reporting period. If a work package hasa duration exceeding 10 days, check or monitoring points should be established within the duration, say,every three to five days, so progress and problems can be identified before too much time has passed.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"65.In a Work Breakdown Structure for a software development project, the typical structure follows the major phasesof software development.Refer to Figure 4.4","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"See Figure 4.4 on Page 112.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"66.Integrating a project's work packages within the organization's management structure is known as work breakdownstructure.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"Work packages are short duration tasks that have a definite start and stop point, consume resources, and representcost.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"67.Scope definitions are usually brief with only one or two pages being typical for small projects.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Scope definition should be as brief as possible but complete; one or two pages are typical for small projects.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"68.A work breakdown structure is frequently used on projects such as software development where the project is focusedon activities rather than deliverables.Refer to Snapshot from Practice on Page114","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"The WBS should conform to how you are going to schedule work. For example, if assignments are made in terms ofdays, then tasks should be limited as best as possible to one day or more to complete. Conversely, if hoursare the smallest unit for scheduling, then work can be broken down to one-hour increments; final activitiesshould have clearly defined start/end events. Avoid open-ended tasks like \"research\" or \"market analysis.\"","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"69.Responsibility matrices are used primarily with small and medium sized projects and have limited use in largeprojects.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"One tool that is widely used by project managers and task force leaders of small projects is the responsibilitymatrix (RM). The RM (sometimes called a linear responsibility chart) summarizes the tasks to be accomplishedand who is responsible for what on a project.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"70.In a work breakdown structure deliverables are ignored and replaced with activities or tasks that have been groupedin phases.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"Once the scope and deliverables have been identified, the work of the project can be successively subdividedinto smaller and smaller work elements. The outcome of this hierarchical process is called the work breakdownstructure (WBS).","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"71.The intersection of the WBS and the OBS represents a control point, called a cost account.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"The intersection of the WBS and OBS represents the set of work packages necessary to complete the subdeliverablelocated immediately above and the organizational unit on the left responsible for accomplishing the packagesat the intersection.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"72.The most commonly used scheme for coding the work breakdown structure is to use a department project number assignedby the accounting department.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"The most commonly used scheme in practice is numeric indention.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"73.For large companies, the organization breakdown structure is used rather than the work breakdown structure.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"The OBS defines the organization subdeliverables in a hierarchical pattern in successively smaller and smallerunits. Frequently, the traditional organization structure can be used. Even if the project is completelyperformed by a team, it is necessary to break down the team structure for assigning responsibility for budgets,time, and technical performance.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"74.The hierarchical work breakdown structure can be used to represent the need for information at various levelsof management.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"The WBS is a map of the project. Use of WBS helps to assure project managers that all products and work elementsare identified, to integrate the project with the current organization, and to establish a basis for control.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"75.The intersection of work packages and the organization unit creates a project control point called a cost account.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"The intersection of the WBS and OBS represents the set of work packages necessary to complete the subdeliverablelocated immediately above and the organizational unit on the left responsible for accomplishing the packagesat the intersection.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"76.Reviews with customers only refers to projects with external customers who are paying for the project.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"Completion of the scope checklist ends with a review with your customer—internal or external. The main concernhere is the understanding and agreement of expectations.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"77.A typical responsibility matrix will include not only those responsible for a specific task but also those whosupply support and assistance.Refer to Figure 4.6","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"See Figure 4.6 on page 117.Short Answer Questions","difficulty":"Short Answer Questions"},{"question":"78.Identify and briefly describe the five steps in defining a project.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. defining the project scope, 2. establishing project priorities, 3. creating the work breakdown structure,4. integrating the WBS with the organization, and 5. coding the WBS","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"79.Identify and briefly describe the six elements on the recommended project scope checklist.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. project objectives, 2. deliverables, 3. milestones, 4. technical requirements, 5. limits and exclusions, and6. reviews with customers","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"80.In terms of project management, what is a deliverable and give an example.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"A deliverable is an expected output that occurs during the life of a project.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"81.Identify and briefly describe the three elements that are traditionally used to measure the ultimate successof a project.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. costs (budget), 2. time (schedule), and 3. performance (scope)","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"82.In project management terms, what is meant by \"managing the trade-offs?\"","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"During project execution decisions will be needed to balance the three success criteria; costs, schedule, andperformance. Typically one will be degraded in order to maintain or improve another. Thus the criteria aretraded off.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"83.Identify and briefly describe the three categories used to classify the priority of major project parameters.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. constrain (the parameter is fixed), 2. enhance (the parameter should be optimized), and 3. accept (lower resultsare acceptable)","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"84.What is a Project Priority Matrix and how would you use one?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"The Project Priority Matrix is a graphic representation classifying the major project parameters of time, performance,and cost according to their priority. It is used to assist in making project trade-off decisions.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"85.What is meant by a work breakdown structure and how does it help manage projects?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"WBS is the logical subdividing of major activities into smaller elements. It is useful to ensure complete planningof a project as well as a basis for monitoring progress.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"86.Identify in order from broadest to most specific, the six parts of the hierarchical breakdown of the WBS.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. project, 2. deliverable, 3. sub deliverable, 4. lowest sub deliverable, 5. cost account, and work package","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"87.What is a Responsibility Matrix and how would it be used in project management?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"The RM summarizes the tasks to be accomplished and who is responsible for what on a project. It is used to ensurethat all participants understand and agree on their assignments.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"88.What is meant by \"Scope Creep\" and why is it significant to project managers?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"It is the gradual expansion of project deliverables to the point that overall project constraints (costs andschedule) can no longer be met.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"89.What is an OBS and how would you use it to plan a project?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"The OBS is the process of defining which organization units are responsible for performing the work outlinedin the individual work packages.4-1","difficulty":"1"}]